environment
variables environment variables there's
other videos for environment variables
and why they matter but with regard to
GitHub actions I already did a video
about this go watch that one it's longer
but I want to emphasize one thing
environment variables
are I think the second best way to pass
data into anything the first best way is
standard input because that's data and
you're in control of parsing it but it's
tedious right so if you don't know what
an environment variable is let's just go
ahead and recap an environment variable
is when you you might look at this and
go where does that user even come from
right well right here is where it comes
from now this entry point is not meant
to be run so I have to run it with
shell um directory see wait no it went
ahead and did it it's trying to create a
directory uh that's that's
that's other problem in there but did
you see this you see here it it it
looked at my user so I can Echo user and
I can see what it is right if I wanted
to change it you probably already know
this but I could say user equals another
and and it would say I mean disregard
the other error but hello another right
so that is what we're talking about when
we're talking about environment varials
we're talking about passing data safely
and easily in a named way into anything
that can run anything that can execute
and well why why does that matter for
GitHub actions because when you look at
a GitHub action um you see all these
environment variables that come across I
already did this in another video but I
really am going to show it to you again
when you use a
GitHub uh when when you set up
environment variables in a GitHub action
you get these nice super duper clean uh
methods of import you don't get this
ugly crap that comes when you use with
uh and you get of course they GI of
itself uses a bunch of standard
environments uh variables as well
another reason to use them so but so
when we go to how to define an
environment variable into an action so
here is our action um you can see that
the environment variables are passed
very cleanly and they're super pretty
and they can pass the secrets in and it
just it's just absolutely beautiful not
only that it's really really secure uh
the other video talked about how this
avoids the problem using with in my
opinion you should never use with at all
and and I made a video about that you
can argue with me all you want on that
that's fine people have been using
environment variables since the CGI days
in the you know 90s and it's a really
safe convenient way to pass data it's
very intuitive because people are
already doing it for containers these
days but there's actually one last
really great reason and if you watched
the all the way to the end of this video
this is where you're going to be
grateful for that one of the things you
can do with environment variables that
you cannot do with the other stuff is
you can move their scope so as it was
right there these environment variables
are set to only be in the scope of this
particular run step but if I wanted to I
can bring them up I can bring one or
more let's say I want to have
essentially managed host key right maybe
we don't want the host key to be maybe
we bring it up here okay now what I'm
trying to say is that because I chose to
use environment variables here instead
of with and some of the other crap I can
actually use the same exact environment
variable and then have it be visible
down here and then I also have the
option to overtake it if I wanted to um
oops I could I could actually leave it
down here and have it be have it be
overridden now anybody who's done any
kind of coding understands the value of
this the the value of overwriting
variables and having some VAR will be
the default not to mention as I already
showed the ultra clean method of input
by naming convention so that your entry
scripts your your whatever your script
is actually can very easily be reused
all by itself outside the scope of a
GitHub environment variable I mean it to
to think about it if if you tried if you
tried to make this entry point script uh
I mean it's already other than the
GitHub uncore output which is is kind of
annoying this is just a script right so
you could have the script anywhere and
it it can make sense to somebody whether
or not it's a part of a gith of action
so so my main point here to this video
is environment variables buy you the
ability to set different scopes of
visibility for your environment
variables throughout your code
throughout your action so that you can
change it up and
that is just intuitive to anybody who's
already been using environment variables
anybody who knows environment variables
will already immediately see the benefit
of that not to mention just the the
Baseline Simplicity I so this video is
advocating very strongly that when
you're using a GitHub action just
default to passing your data through
environment variables or into a file
right and specifically you know get a
output file which is the really the only
way to do that for large amounts of data
um I'm still relatively new to GitHub
actions so if you uh yeah I if you have
a better way to do this or you think I'm
dead wrong please let me know in the
comments um and I'll try to get to them
and we but but the takeaway is just use
environment variables in your get up
actions